Planned Parenthood League of Massachusetts, 1859-2002 (bulk 1916-1960)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Miscellaneous individuals
    - Johnson, Chandler W. 1941 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Jones, Barbara Norman 1936 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Jones, Eleanor Dwight 1930-33 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Jones, Ted 1948-49 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - K 1933-57 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Kapp, M. A. 1936-67 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Keller, Helen 1942 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Kennedy, John F. 1957, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Kimball, Maria 1939-40 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Kirkham, William B. 1935-40 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Kleinman, Elizabeth Z., M.D. 1932, 1936, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Knowles, Alice J. 1936-41, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Konikow, Antoinette F., M.D. 1929-42 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Konikow, Moses J., M.D. 1935 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - L 1931-57, 1961, undated (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
    - Lamont, Florenceundated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Lawrence, Charles H. 1935-40 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Lee, Mary 1930-36 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Lennox, William G., M.D. 1937-50 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Leverone, Louise M., M.D. 1933 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Lindey, Alexander 1938-40 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Little, Eleanor 1936, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Little, Leon 1932-37 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot 1936 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Lord, Milton Edward 1940 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Lord-Heinstein, Lucille, M.D. 1937, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Lyle, Eveline B., M.D. 1932-34 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - M 1931-55 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Macomber, Donald, M.D. 1934-37, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Mann, Albert Z. 1937-43 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Mann, Margaret 1937, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Marindin, Eleanor B. 1933-41 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Marshall, Jessie Ames 1931-35 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Mather, Philip R. 1946, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Matsner, Eric M., M.D. 1932-38 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - McCormick, Katharine Dexter 1942, 1959-68 (Box 15, Folder 33-34)
    - McGann, The Very Reverend John M. 1933-39 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - McKinnon, Edna Rankin 1957 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - McPeak, Alice 1957 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Meigs, Joe Vincent, M.D. 1935-37 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Mendum, Samuel W. 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Moore, Allison Pierce 1935-38, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Moore, Cecile Stieler, M.D. 1937-38 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Morse, Theresa 1939-41 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Myrdal, Alva 1939-40 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar 1938 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - N 1934-42, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Neilson, W. A. 1940 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Newcomb, Russell 1938 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Nixon, Richard M. 1960 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - O 1932-48, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Olan, Levi, Rabbi 1940-42 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - P 1932-67, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Patch, Marion 1937-42 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Peabody, Endicott 1937 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Perkins, Georgia 1937, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Phillips, Caroline D. 1936 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Pierce, C. C., M.D. 1943 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Pilpel, Harriet F. 1940-51 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Pincus, Gregory, M.D. 1958 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Pollock, Henry M., M.D. 1937 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Pool, Beekman H. 1946-47 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Potter, Mary D. 1940-41 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Powers, Walter, Jr. 1956-57 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Pratt, Edwin H. R. 1947-48 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Prince, Marjorie B. 1935-39 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - R 1928-66, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Reid, Duncan E., M.D. 1947-53 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Reynolds, T. M. 1935 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Riggs, Austin Fox, M.D. 1932-39 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Ripley, Ida S. 1935, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Robey, William H., M.D. 1940-43 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Robinson, Thomas L. 1946-47 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Rock, John, M.D. 1936-59 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Rockefeller, Nancy Carnegie 1936, undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Rose, Florence 1932-43 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Rose, D. Kenneth 1938-48, undated (Box 16, Folder 38-39)
    - Rugg, Charles B. 1940-41 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - S 1933-65, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Sanger, Margaret 1928-56, undated, [See also SERIES IV. RELATED ORGANIZATIONS - Miscellaneous organizations - BCCRB, MSRB, NCFLBC, IPPF; SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES -Individuals; SERIES VIII. CLIPPINGS AND ARTICLES; SERIES X. MICROFILM] (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Scull, James H. 1945-46 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Shipton, George M. 1947-55 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Simpson, Russell G. 1958-60, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Smith, George Gilbert, M.D. 1931-52, undated (Box 17, Folder 6-10)
    - Solomon, Maida H. 1936-39, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Southard, Margaret Lee 1940, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Sprague, Howard B., M.D. 1939-47 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Stokey, Roger P. 1955-64 (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Stone, Abraham, M.D. 1939-43 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Stone, Hannah M., M.D. 1932-40 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Sturgis, Somers, M.D. 1936-63 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Sugrue, Thomas 1952 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - T 1932-48, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Taft, Robert A. 1948 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Tamblyn, Ronald J. 1940-41 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Toll, Charles H. 1940, 1948-49 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Topping, Ruth 1933-34 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Trowbridge, Reverend Cornelius C. 1937-48, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Tyrer, A. H., Reverend 1935-37 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - U-V 1934-38 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Vaughan, Samuel 1936-45 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Vogt, William 1951-60 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - W 1918, 1932-60, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Wallis, Frank B. 1941-49 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Watson, Mary B. 1935-39 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Watson, Paul B. 1935 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Welch, Margaret P. 1934-48, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Whitenack, Janet B. 1935-38 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Whiteside, Alexander 1935, 1938, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Wilder, Marion 1936-37 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Wilkins, Raymond S. 1937 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Willcox, M. A. 1932-42 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Williams, Olive B., M.D. 1933 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Williams, Sydney M. 1940-42 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Willson, Edith E. 1937 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Willson, Prentiss, M.D. 1940-41 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Winslow, Charles-Edward A. 1937-38 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Winsor, M. P. 1936-39, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Wissmann, Mrs. H. B. 1954-55 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Wood, Mabel Travis 1935-40 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Woodbury, M. L. 1930-36, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Woodward, W. C. 1938 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - X - Z 1939-48 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Zimmerman, Carl Z. 1940-41 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Zutter, Louise 1932-36 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Subjects
    - Appreciation 1935-39 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Inquiries
      - Adoption 1946-56 (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Artificial insemination 1946 (Box 18, Folder 26)
      - Birth control 1932-41 (Box 19, Folder 1-16)
        [closed until 2010]
      - Birth control 1942-58 (Box 20, Folder 1-11)
      - Fertility 1946-55 (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
      - Marriage counseling 1939-54 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - RH Factor 1947 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Rhythm method 1934-56 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Sex education 1956 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Sterilization 1947-53 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous 1932-56, undated (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
    - Letters to the editor 1929-55 (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
    - Opposition
      - Birth control 1930-51 (Box 21, Folder 15-18)
      - Massachusetts Mothers' Health Council 1932-43 (Box 21, Folder 19-20)
      - Planned Parenthood of Massachusetts 1947-56, undated (Box 21, Folder 21-29)
      - Doctors 1947-48 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Other birth control leagues, [see also SERIES VII. RESOURCE FILES - Countries - U.S.]
      - Alaska and Arkansas 1964 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Colorado 1948-57 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Connecticut 1932-41 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - District of Columbia 1945-58 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Japan 1950-52 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Minnesota and Missouri 1935, 1950, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - New York 1935, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Pennsylvania 1945-58 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Ohio 1933-54 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Rhode Island 1931-61 (Box 22, Folder 10-11)
      - Virginia 1932-51 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Wisconsin 1934, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Support 1932-55, undated (Box 22, Folder 14-16)
    - U.S. Post Office - mailing of contraceptives 1934-40 (Box 22, Folder 17)
- SERIES II. STAFF
  - Ames, Blanche Ames 1935 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Belisle, Eugene 1941-42, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Campbell, Loraine Leeson, [see also SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINSTRATIVE FILES - Photographs]
    - Articles and clippings 1956-72 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Diary 1959 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Interviews
      - Msgr. Francis J. Lally 1962 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Msgr. Thomas J. Riley 1952 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia 1959-68, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Writings
      - Notes 1935-65, undated (Box 23, Folder 8-9)
      - Publications 1940-48 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Speeches and talks 1940-57, undated, [see also SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINSTRATIVE FILES- PPLM - Publicity-Speeches] (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Statements
        - Subcommittee on Public welfare 1960 (Box 23, Folder 12)
        - Miscellaneous 1940-60, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Oral History: by James Reed for the Schlesinger-Rockefeller Oral History Project 1973-74 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Cannon, Cornelia James 1954-66 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Clothier, Florence 1957, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Everts, Beth 1971 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Plank, Stephen, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Sagoff, Hazel
    - Biographical material
      - Articles and clippings 1930-71 (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Retirement 1969 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Radcliffe Institute application 1968-69, undated (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - Writings 1968 (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous 1948-52 (Box 23, Folder 23)
- SERIES III. CENTRAL ADMINISTRATIVE FILES
  - Earliest birth control organizations, [see also Birth Control League of Massachusetts - History] (Box 24)
    - Allison Birth Control Defense League and Birth Control League of Massachusetts 1916-19 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Family Welfare Foundation 1919-20 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Emergency Defense Committee 1928-29 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Birth Control League of Massachusetts
    - Annual meetings and dinners
      - Invitations 1929-39 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Minutes 1930-39 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous 1935-38 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Annual reports 1930-39 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Committees
      - General instructions, form letters and notices 1933-39 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Contacts
        - Minutes 1937-38, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
        - Organizations
          - Charitable 1934-35, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
          - Educational 1933-34 (Box 24, Folder 11)
          - Medical 1934-39 (Box 24, Folder 12)
          - Religious 1935-37, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
          - Social welfare 1934-38, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
          - Miscellaneous 1934-41 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Executive
        - Correspondence 1932-39 (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - Minutes 1931-38 (Box 25, Folder 2-11)
      - Finance, [See Financial materials] (Box 25)
      - Headquarters 1936-38 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Health extension 1935-39 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Library research 1936-38 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Medical 1939, [see also Physicians Committee for the Defense of Medical Rights] (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Medical consultants 1932-38, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Meetings
        - Reports and minutes 1933-39 (Box 25, Folder 17)
        - Speakers
          - Form letters and miscellaneous correspondence 1932-37 (Box 25, Folder 18)
          - Invitations 1937 (Box 25, Folder 19)
          - Lists and possible speakers 1932-37 (Box 26, Folder 1)
          - Offers to speak 1936-37 (Box 26, Folder 2)
          - Refusals 1932-37 (Box 26, Folder 3)
          - Reports 1938-39 (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
          - Requests 1935-37 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Membership
        - Correspondence and form letters 1929-37, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
        - Enrollment data 1935-38 (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - Membership lists 1930-31 (Box 26, Folder 9)
        - Minutes and annual reports 1935-39 (Box 26, Folder 10)
        - Budgets and miscellaneous material 1935-37, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Men's Advisory 1938-39 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Mother's Health
        - Correspondence
          - Form letters 1940-42 (Box 26, Folder 13)
          - Miscellaneous 1935-42 (Box 26, Folder 14)
        - Financial materials 1937-38, [see also Mother's Health Office - Financial materials] (Box 26, Folder 15)
        - Meetings agenda, minutes, and reports 1932-42 (Box 26, Folder 16)
        - Publicity
          - Advertising 1942 (Box 26, Folder 17)
          - Press releases 1942 (Box 26, Folder 18)
        - Referendum, [see also SERIES VI. LEGISLATATIVE FILES - Initiative and Referendum Campaign, 1940-42]
          - Correspondence 1942 (Box 26, Folder 19)
          - Printed material 1942 (Box 26, Folder 20)
          - Radio scripts 1940-42 (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Nominating 1932-40 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - President's Council 1935-39 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Publicity 1934-39, [see also Publications] (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Steering 1938-39 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Welfareundated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Constitution, by-laws, and policies 1916-38, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Financial materials
      - Appeal letters 1932-37, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Budgets, expenses, and miscellaneous financial records 1935-38 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence from contributors 1931-33, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Dues and contributions
        - Lists and receipts 1933-37 (Box 27, Folder 10-11)
        - Summary 1934-35 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Finance campaigns
        - Acknowledgements 1932-37 (Box 27, Folder 13)
        - Emergency relief campaign 1934-35 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Defense Fund
          - Campaign solicitors 1937 (Box 28, Folder 2)
          - Correspondence 1934-37, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - Plans 1934-38, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Worker's Manual 1935 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous 1935, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Finance committee 1934-39, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Treasurer's reports 1929-39 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous 1935, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - History 1934-37, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Hospital statements approving birth control 1937 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Mother's Health Office
      - Administration
        - Committees
          - Central 1937-38 (Box 28, Folder 12)
          - Medical Committee of Supervising Physicians 1937, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
          - Mother's Health Office
            - Meetings 1936-39, undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
            - Organization 1931-37, undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
        - American Birth Control League 1935-37 (Box 28, Folder 16)
        - Office inventories, insurance, etc. 1937-40, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
        - Officers and consultants lists 1935-38, undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
        - Organizational plans 1930-32, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
        - Personnel applications 1937, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Annual meetings and reports 1937 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Clinics, [see also Social services - Social workers - Reports]
        - General
          - Case histories 1935, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
          - Closing, [see also SERIES X. MICROFILM]
            - Clippings 1937 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
            - Correspondence, forms, lists, and printed material 1936-39, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
          - Management policies and plans 1937, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Andover 1939 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Boston
          - Brookline, [see also SERIES VI. LEGISLATIVE FILES - History and background-Cases - Brookline Clinic]
            - Accounts and finances 1932-38, undated, [see also Mother's Health Committee- Financial materials] (Box 29, Folder 7)
            - Constitution 1931-35 (Box 29, Folder 8)
            - Office leases 1933-36 (Box 29, Folder 9)
            - Reports
              - Annual and semi-annual 1932-37, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
              - Monthly 1933-37 (Box 29, Folder 11)
            - Rhythm clinics 1937-42 (Box 29, Folder 12)
            - Miscellaneous 1933-37, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
          - Brookline and Greater Boston committee meetings 1932-36 (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
          - Brookline and South End reports 1936-38 (Box 30, Folder 4)
          - South End
            - Finances 1936, undated, [see also Mother's Health Committee -Financial materials] (Box 30, Folder 5)
            - Announcements, planning notes, and minutes 1936, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
            - Reports 1937 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Fall Riverundated (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Fitchburg 1937 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - New Bedford 1934-38 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        - North Shore 1936-38 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        - Salem 1936-39, undated, [see also SEREIS IV. LEGISLATIVE FILES- History and background cases - Brookline and Salem Clinic] (Box 30, Folder 12)
        - Springfield 1935-39, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
        - Webster 1939 (Box 30, Folder 14)
        - Worcester
          - Monthly reports 1935-37 (Box 30, Folder 15)
          - Miscellaneous 1932-39, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
        - Miscellaneous 1937, undated (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - Financial materials, [see also Committees - Mother's Health - Financial materials]
        - Accounts and miscellaneous 1937-38, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - Costs and fees, notes, and analysis 1934-37, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
        - Financial summaries and salaries 1935-38, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
        - Fund drive 1935, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
        - Treasurer's reports 1935-37 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Forms
        - Clinic reports 1937, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
        - Letters 1933-35, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Medical consultants 1932-38 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Publicity (speeches) 1937-38 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Referrals 1933-37, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Reports
        - BCLM Executive Board 1936-37 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous 1932-37 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Research 1937 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Social services
        - Social workers
          - "A Maternal Health Center Reviews Its Patients" 1939 (Box 31, Folder 14)
          - Reports and follow-ups 1934-38, undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
        - Miscellaneous 1936-37, undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous notesundated (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Personnel
      - Applications 1932-39, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - Educational Director and Field Secretary (Caroline Davis) 1931-40 (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - Executive director
        - Reports (Mary White) 1930-41 (Box 31, Folder 20)
        - Selection 1939, undated (Box 31, Folder 21)
      - Field Director (Doris Rutledge) 1937-39 (Box 31, Folder 22)
      - Lists 1934-41, undated (Box 31, Folder 23)
      - Publicity Director applications 1938-39 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Plans and policies 1931-39 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Publicity
      - Advertisements 1935, undated, [see also Printed materials] (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Advertising dispute (Ames/Cannon) 1935, [see also Committees - Publicity and SERIES X. MICROFILM] (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Book lists and bibliographies 1933-37, undated, [see also Box 34] (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Essay contest 1935-36, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Exhibits 1935, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Finances
        - Fund raising campaign, Stoddard Sampson Co. 1935 (Box 32, Folder 7)
        - Printing and mailing 1935, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Form letters
        - Clergy 1933-38, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - Hospital administrators 1935, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
        - Members 1932-36 (Box 32, Folder 11)
        - Parent's Petition 1934 (Box 32, Folder 12)
        - Physicians 1934-37, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
        - State sponsors 1937 (Box 32, Folder 14)
        - Women's clubs and other groups 1934-38, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
        - Miscellaneous 1938-39, undated (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Invitations 1931-37, undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Newspapers 1934-39 (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - Press releases 1934-39 (Box 32, Folder 19-22)
      - Printed material 1930-38, undated (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Radio
        - Correspondence and lists 1932-35 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Scripts 1931-35, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Speeches 1933-39, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Reports 1932-38, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Research
      - Boston contraceptive centers project 1937 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Contraceptives and life insurance 1938-39 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - "Medical Status of Birth Control: An inquiry into medical action on Contraception" 1934 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Notes 1932-42, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - U.S. mail and contraceptives 1934 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Writings 1938, undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - State sponsors
      - Correspondence
        - Acceptances 1935-37 (Box 33, Folder 11)
        - Regrets 1935 (Box 33, Folder 12)
        - Miscellaneous 1932-35 (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Lists and form letters 1937-39 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Statements and resolutions 1936-38 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Card file of books and articles (Box 34)
  - Massachusetts Mothers' Health Council
    - Annual reports 1940-41 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Board of directors
      - Correspondence 1939-45 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Meetings and minutes 1939-45 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Committees
      - Executive
        - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports 1940, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
        - Minutes and notes 1939-45 (Box 35, Folder 5-8)
        - Test case 1939 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Field 1939-45 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Nominating 1938-45 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Public relations, [see Publicity] (Box 35)
      - Constitution 1939-45 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Financial materials
      - Annual auditor's reports 1940-45 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Budget campaigns
        - Lists and form letters 1939 (Box 36, Folder 2)
        - Lists of names 1940 (Box 36, Folder 3)
        - Newsletter 1939-42 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - Budgets 1938-44 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Finance and fund raising committees 1939-42 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - Records and statements 1939-43 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Tax information 1938-42, undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - History 1942-43, undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Medical Rights Referendum, [see also SERIES VI. LEGISLATIVE FILES - Initiative and Referendum Campaign, 1940-42]
      - Form letters 1941-42 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Master plan 1942 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - National Committee for Medical Rights in Massachusetts
        - Memos, form letter, lists, and statements 1942 (Box 36, Folder 12)
        - Responses to invitations 1942 (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Publicity: printed materials 1942, [see also Publicity - Printed materials] (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous 1940-42, undated (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Meetings
      - Annual 1939-45 (Box 36, Folder 16)